<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JoElla Straley</title>
    <description>A place for charts and graphs.
</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 11:57:20 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 11:57:20 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Work On The European Commission Website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/UnitedStates.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Old scorecard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Is my country within the one average absolute deviation from the median??&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
When I started working at this organization last year, I saw the above table &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt;. It’s almost standard in every presentation and report, but its Excel-ness made it exceedingly clunky to use and impossible to style with complete freedom. I knew what I wanted to do: recreate the “scorecard” for the web. I started in on the project with the goal of making it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;easy to load (Excel with its “1 processor(s)” sets a low bar here)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;more legible/hierarchical&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;easy to swap out datasets from other index projects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;downloadable as an image file for use in slides and reports&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I came up with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/regional_policy/en/information/maps/social_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/scorecard.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of scorecard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Be thankful for UTF-8 encoding&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
As it turned out, this project found an almost immediate use with the European Regional Social Project Index. The European Commission asked us to provide some visuals to go with the beta version’s publication, and I was able to make some adjustments to fit their defined page widths and ship it out in a matter of days. Success!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-it-made-out-of&quot;&gt;What’s It Made Out Of?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the “visualization” piece of this project isn’t that sophisticated, I built these scorecards using D3. D3 has a handy set of functions for stats-type math, and it also provides a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macwright.org/2013/07/07/d3-for-html.html&quot;&gt;clean way to think about templating&lt;/a&gt;. It’s in a different universe from Excel speed-wise, but there is still a ton of math happening under the hood, which makes it a tidge slow to load. Still not bad. It wasn’t until I started testing on other browsers that I really started to wonder about my choice to put so much math in JavaScript – who knew there were different ways to implement “sort”!! (Computer science grads, maybe?). The benefit is that we now have a one step process of bringing in a new datasheet to make scorecards for a different index project. Still, I’m not convinced this is a huge advantage over separating the process of defining the boundaries of “above average”/”below average” in an R script. I’m still working on that question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;update-prying-it-out-of-the-browser&quot;&gt;Update: Prying It Out Of The Browser&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project that went to the EC site missed one of the goals above: it can’t be downloaded as an image. In this iteration you see a failed attempt to make that possible via SVG Crowbar. Every bit of the chart is actually SVG to allow the Crowbar to work, but in the end the project never came out of the page with all the CSS styles. Installing a Chrome extension to pry out images from a website is a bit of a big ask for most users anyway, so I abandoned this path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searching for another way, I looked into using html canvas and libraries that convert these into image files. Perfect, I thought, not using HTML/CSS for text layout sucks anyway! I ripped everything up and started over with a much more semantic approach, and found happily that &lt;a href=&quot;http://cburgmer.github.io/rasterizeHTML.js/&quot;&gt;rasterizeHTML&lt;/a&gt; does a great job of converting the screen graphics, even going between retina and non-retina displays. My design also got lighter and better once I had some of my old friends like “border” and “div” back in town. Everybody wins!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example I downloaded from the browser as a .png:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/mauritius.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New scorecard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Data embargoed! Can&#39;t wait to show you the real thing in about a month&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
In summary, everyone likes this scorecard better than the clunky old Excel file, and it meets all the objectives above. Still, the way it illustrates the concept of “relative performance” is unchanged. I wonder what I could do if I started from the ground up to make this rather complex idea a bit more intelligible. I hope to have an update on that process sometime soon.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/update/2016/05/10/eu-scorecards.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/update/2016/05/10/eu-scorecards.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Work Projects From 2015</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are a few notable projects from my year. Notable, at least, to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.renewoureconomy.org/voterinteractive/&quot;&gt;first interactive&lt;/a&gt; I worked on as an actual professional being paid cash money. I was the main developer on the project, with a lot of guidance from my excellent colleague, Reed Spool, for which I will always be grateful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.renewoureconomy.org/voterinteractive/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/elexmap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a lot better at d3 and JavaScript after this project!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the year I started working at the Social Progress Imperative. My title here is “graphic designer”, so I made myself a business card:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/bizcards.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Biz card&quot; /&gt;
(And I made new ones for everyone else at the company.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps even more exciting than the business cards, I created slides for our director’s second &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/michael_green_how_we_can_make_the_world_a_better_place_by_2030?language=en&quot;&gt;TED Talk&lt;/a&gt; given in London last September at TED Global. The scatterplot is a perennial at SPI, since our mission is to advance this index as a measure of things left out of GDP, notably the things that actually make life better. The fact that some countries are so far over or under the curve demonstrates that GDP doesn’t automatically convert to what we describe as “social progress”, as measured by “indicators” like “water and sanitation”, “access to basic knowledge”, “nutrition and basic medical care”, “personal rights”, etc for a whole society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/TED-slide.png&quot; alt=&quot;TED slides&quot; /&gt;
I focused on making these legible from far away in a dark room: dark background, strong contrast, minimal markings on the charts. Reportedly (via Michael Green) these received compliments from the TED Global people!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I got married and went absolutely nuts creating the main image for our wedding website (excerpted here). This strange obsession taught me a lot about Illustrator and the importance of having some kind of color palette.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/town2-01.svg&quot; alt=&quot;The view from town&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also did a few other things for my job, like an &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.socialprogressimperative.org/blog/posts/do-smoking-habits-change-with-social-progress&quot;&gt;interactive scatterplot&lt;/a&gt;, layout for print products, HTML emails (gasp!) and these little quickie ads for Twitter (design and copy):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/socprogress/status/671728387984109568&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/access-basic-know.png&quot; alt=&quot;#givingtuesday ads&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, InDesign accomplishment of the year: figuring out how to run Arabic text (right-to-left) in the same line with English numbers (left-to-right) for these translated versions of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/socprogress/status/680359982076944384&quot;&gt;People’s Report Card&lt;/a&gt;, a collaborative project with Global Citizen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not pictured:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also during my stint at Graphicacy, I worked on their annual Death &amp;amp; Taxes poster, a visualization of the federal budget. It’s a lot of circles. Reed and I began work on a project to create the poster in JavaScript instead of R, reasoning that a web browser is a good place for graphics, and we could get closer to the final (bringing in images, for example) before pulling everything into Illustrator with SVG Crowbar for the actual print poster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made a pretty sweet circle generator that pumped out one branch of goverment at a time in a ring of circles. We also created some fun layout tools that would allow a designer to adjust the radius of the outer ring and spacing among subdepartments on it before exporting into the layout. It’s a bit hard to explain, better to show, but the project isn’t online. I did learn that trigonometry is kind of fascinating (if you’ve forgotten how it works, read about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://processing.org/tutorials/trig/&quot;&gt;“unit circle”&lt;/a&gt; - triangles control the circle!). The math makes a lot more sense when you’re using it to actually accomplish something than it did when you were a pimply pre-teen just freaking out that Mr. Bergzolf would catch you chewing gum or give you a D. SOH-CAH-TOA!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I don’t have the work to show for that, here’s a &lt;a href=&quot;http://graphicacy.com/can-raw-data-be-cooked/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; I wrote about my best guess for explaining negative numbers in the federal budget. I was particularly proud of my little bar graph. What great colors! I think it really has the look of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://graphicacy.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/crimevictimsfund.png&quot; alt=&quot;Bar graph from blog post&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/update/2015/12/26/year-in-review.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/update/2015/12/26/year-in-review.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interactive Scatterplot</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.socialprogressimperative.org/blog/posts/do-smoking-habits-change-with-social-progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/spi-smoking.png&quot; alt=&quot;Does smoking cause social progress?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few months ago I started working at a non-profit that promotes national welfare index. Needless to say, this organization deals with a great deal of data, and part of my job is to think of presentations of it. I produced an interactive scatterplot of smoking rates (for men and women separately) vs. social progress as some blog fodder during a slow August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smoking has nothing to do with health performance, it turns out, but there is an interesting observation to be had about nations with higher female smoking rates. Read &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.socialprogressimperative.org/blog/posts/do-smoking-habits-change-with-social-progress&quot;&gt;my post&lt;/a&gt; to find out more.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/update/2015/07/05/smoking.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/update/2015/07/05/smoking.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Class Project</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/finalproject.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/different.png&quot; alt=&quot;LiquidLab project&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just realized that I never added the final version of the fictitious juice company website I created for a graphic design class this spring. I never did find just the right pic online, so I’m leading with what might be the world’s first arm-only selfie (feat. beets!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What did I learn from this exercise? It’s hard to deal with all the content your “client” (or school project prompt) suggests you add in. The idea of this fake company is that they get people to subscribe to their custom juicing plans, saving them time and improving their diet. But the description in the prompt felt a bit confused on that tip - lots of information about about farming practices, serious hand holding prior to seeing the actual lifestyle survey… Don’t these busy people want to cut through all that crap and start chugging acai berries already?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the in-class review by local DC design professionals, I was repeatedly reminded that too much text is a bad thing. I wished I would have stuck with my instinct to simplify the content and come up with a more elegant site that felt right for the purpose. I’ve always found class projects challenging. Making up the rationale behind these imaginary people stretches your creative brain in the opposite way you need it to go for a real workplace scenario. In reality, the last thing you want to do is fill in a lot of blanks about what a customer wants. But in this case, since there was no real customer, I would have been better off accepting the prompt as a safe space for experimenting. After all, when facing real clients who don’t go along with every suggestion, it’s probably good to have the confidence that comes from having experiences where your instincts turned out to be right.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/update/2015/07/05/design-class-project.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/update/2015/07/05/design-class-project.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Birds Of Prey!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/projects/birdsofprey.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/birdsofprey.png&quot; alt=&quot;Birds of prey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was looking around for some design prompts online and found a decent collection at &lt;a href=&quot;http://briefbox.me&quot;&gt;Briefbox&lt;/a&gt;. The first prompt to catch my eye asked for an infographic on &lt;a href=&quot;http://briefbox.me/design-brief/birds-of-prey-infographic/&quot;&gt;“birds of prey”&lt;/a&gt;. The Briefbox people suggest looking at Wikipedia, which I did, only to be overwhelmed and bored by an academic account of phylogenic studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The phylogeny of Accipitriformes is complex and difficult to unravel. Widespread paraphylies were observed in many phylogenetic studies. Unfortunately more recent and detailed studies are shown similar results. However, according to the findings of a 2014 study, the sister relationship between larger clades of Accipitriformes was well supported (e.g. relationship of Harpagus kites to buzzards and sea eagles and these latter two with Accipiter hawks are sister taxa of the clade containing Aquilinae and Harpiinae).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While science is totally of amazing, sometimes the way it’s presented on Wikipedia just makes one despair* of finding enough interesting, linear nuggets to make a little infographic story. So what did I do? I made some shit up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have also used &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.catipsum.com/&quot;&gt;Cat Ipsum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Meowing non stop for food plan steps for world domination but lick arm hair. Find something else more interesting intently stare at the same spot lick butt, for hate dog poop on grasses, chase laser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Yeah, but… not for long! I learned about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secretarybird&quot;&gt;secretarybird&lt;/a&gt; from this article. Have you seen this thing??&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/update/2015/06/11/birds-of-prey.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/update/2015/06/11/birds-of-prey.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Layout Time</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/liquidlab.png&quot; alt=&quot;Liquid Lab Layout&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liquid Lab saves your time, health and money. Or just the first two… maybe. Actually it does nothing. It’s a fake company. I’m only crafting a layout for its website because I’m taking a course on graphic design, and this was the assignment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is a decent stab at doing a simple layout, but it’s not that interesting. And it looks more like a poster than a website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally I wanted a simple white background, a well lit photo, bold sans serif text taking charge over the image. I thought that might feel like “you’re busy, you’re hip, you’re healthy - you want this juice”. However, I have yet to lay hands on such a photo- I’m going with what I find in the Creative Commons search (thanks and credit to Flickr user Stiftelsen Elektronikkbransjen for the photo!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would describe the sentiment behind this piece as: the vegetable pile is sort of like your chaotic life, and you’re glad to have someone else deal with it, blending it down into a sweet-ish, no-chew-required, food paste (“juicing”). I was just working with some phrasing like “Liquid Lab deals with these guys”, but I’m not entirely satisfied yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll be sure to let you know what I come up with.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2015 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/update/2015/04/21/liquid-lab.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/update/2015/04/21/liquid-lab.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Lot Of Tail</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;GIFs are hilarious. It’s great to watch just the funniest part of a &lt;a href=&quot;http://procatinator.com/images/tumblr_lkx04suye01qe1ucbo1_400.gif&quot;&gt;cat’s neurotic drive&lt;/a&gt; to bust through cardboard realized over and over again. Maybe they’re also sorta funny because that repetition is so unnatural. IDK. It would be great fun to really put my finger on exactly why a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ohmagif.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/03/cute-rabbit-falling-asleep.gif&quot;&gt;bunny falling asleep at his work station&lt;/a&gt; is so hilarious, but I think that could also turn into a life’s work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, have you noticed there are a lot of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jeanniejeannie.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/tumblr_mkc10ltCHw1qj6juso1_500.gif&quot;&gt;subtle uses&lt;/a&gt; of animation out there? I love how it only takes a little movement on screen to captivate me, and the stiller it is the more peaceful I feel. It’s a bit like the old days when we just watched TV for fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of sites seem to be using background video this way (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/&quot;&gt;AirBNB&lt;/a&gt;: “Ah, I will be so relaxed staying in that total stranger’s home!”). Subtlety has arrived in GIF-land as well. Last night I came across a great &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzzfeed.com/kevintang/20-insanely-talented-gif-illustrators-you-should-follow?sub=3128308_2704994#.ba7wVOwAOQ&quot;&gt;roundup&lt;/a&gt; from BuzzFeed (!) of artists working with GIFs and decided, dangit, I want to try that, too. So this is where I got, just using layers in PhotoShop. If I do this again I think I will adhere to &lt;a href=&quot;http://tabletopwhale.com/2014/11/03/how-to-make-an-animated-infographic.html&quot;&gt;Tabletop Whale’s&lt;/a&gt; tutorial. She seems like she knows what she’s doing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/cat-wag.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Wag the cat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Apr 2015 06:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/update/2015/04/18/cat-wag.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/update/2015/04/18/cat-wag.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mapping Jobs Data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/projects/census/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/jobmap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve done a few basic heatmaps at work and wanted to take what I had learned and put it toward some “interesting” data. I thought it would be fun to do something with the 2012 Economic Census, so I went after some low hanging mapping fruit (gross) and put together &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/census/index.html&quot;&gt;this piece&lt;/a&gt; that displays either the “job births” or “job destructions” counted in each of our nation’s 280+ lovely MSAs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my time so far has been spent on organizing the program to work efficiently. Since there are 8 survey years available (1977 to 2012), 280+ MSAs and something like 5 subcategories for each (depending on business size/age) preserving this dataset inside the program as something you can work with takes quite a bit of folding and unfolding. To understand d3’s nesting functions better I spent some quality time with Mr. Nester. (Pro-tip: you can actually paste your data into this site and work with nesting statements there. It’s a lot like using the console, but somehow easier.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things I’m happy with: I used q.js to organize the flow of tasks through the program. I was able to borrow a lot of the structure from previous work projects, and doing it all over again brought a little solidity to the lesson. Getting the data once and then organizing and reorganizing it later adds a little speed - but nothing helped me more than realizing I had to pair down my dataset before I joined the data and started appending svgs (confession: in my first stab at this map, I had something like 12,000 DOM nodes).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I have at this point is a basic, functioning map. I’m looking forward to setting up a few more options. As mentioned, the data identifies companies by size and age. Since there’s always so much chatter about the importance of small businesses being “job creators”, I thought it would be interesting to see if any trends become evident on the map.
Making this map also made me think about how, in some ways, every heatmap/quantity map just becomes a map of the population. In this map, clearly New York and other large cities create and lose a ton of jobs. They also have a ton of people. I wonder whether adding a basic population heatmap as the base of the whole project would provide meaningful context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I haven’t done any real work on a layout. I’d like to do a little more research on the data and theories around it, and write some interesting intro-text. I could see this being one of 3-4 views on the data, all packed into one page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping that this basic, functional map is just the beginning of a rich project!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 11:54:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/2015/03/21/job-map.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2015/03/21/job-map.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>First Post</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m creating a space to collect my work as I experiment with graphics and web interactives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/symbols.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;My drawing&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 06:29:29 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/update/2015/03/20/first-post.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/update/2015/03/20/first-post.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
