<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JoElla Straley</title>
    <description>A place for charts and graphs.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 19:40:53 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2017 19:40:53 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.2</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>NLC Pension Report</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I did layout and graphics for this report that details how municipal governments have handled pension obligations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nlc.org/sites/default/files/2017-03/MakingInformedChangestoPublicSectorPensionPlans.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pension.png&quot; alt=&quot;Pension report cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 11:54:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/17/pension-report.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/03/17/pension-report.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Where Do States Preempt City Governments?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My new workplace, National League of Cities, advocates for municipal goverments in Washington. They also study issues that affect local government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this report I was asked to create a graphic of the 50 states showing seven policy areas where states commonly limit what individual cities can do. Click on the image for the report, &lt;em&gt;City Rights in an Era of Preemption: A State-by-State Analysis&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nlc.org/sites/default/files/2017-02/NLC%20Preemption%20Report%202017.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Preemption.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wheel of 50 states with preemption policies&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Mar 2017 11:54:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/03/17/preemption.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/03/17/preemption.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rio de Janeiro &amp; Social Progress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It so happens that partners in Brazil completed a Social Progress Index for the administrative regions of Rio de Janeiro just months before the Olympics. Seizing on this opportunity to promote SPI’s work, our director flew to Rio and presented the index to journalists covering not the games, but the city around the games. I created this map to be handed out to reporters at the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/Rio-Olympics-SPI-map-large.png&quot; alt=&quot;Map of social progress in Rio de Janeiro&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/update/2016/08/29/rio-map.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/update/2016/08/29/rio-map.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Olympics &amp; Social Progress</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A handful of Twitter graphics comparing Olympic medal count with social progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/Olympic-medals-US.png&quot; alt=&quot;Comparison of US Olympic medal wins to social progress performance&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/Olympic-medals-RU.png&quot; alt=&quot;Comparison of Russian Olympic medal wins to social progress performance&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/Olympic-medals-China.png&quot; alt=&quot;Comparison of Chinese Olympic medal wins to social progress performance&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2016 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/update/2016/08/29/forgotten-cards.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/update/2016/08/29/forgotten-cards.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Redesigning SPI Scorecards (Again)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started working at this organization last year, I began to see this table &lt;em&gt;a lot&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/UnitedStates.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Old scorecard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Is my country within the one average absolute deviation from the median??&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s almost standard in every presentation and report, but it’s nearly impossible to read. I set out to make this legible and professional looking, and to pry it out of Excel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my initial remake:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/regional_policy/en/information/maps/social_progress&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/scorecard.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of scorecard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Scorecards displayed on European Commission website for the Beta version of the EU Regional Social Progress Index. (Be thankful for UTF-8 encoding)&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##What’s It Made Out Of?##
Even though the “visualization” piece of this project isn’t that sophisticated, I built these scorecards using D3. I found D3’s set of functions for stats-type math to be very handy, and D3 also provides a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.macwright.org/2013/07/07/d3-for-html.html&quot;&gt;clean way to think about templating&lt;/a&gt;. It’s in a different universe from Excel speed-wise, but there is still a ton of math happening under the hood, which makes it a tidge slow to load, and also, vulnerable to crossbrowser weirdness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;##Getting Image Files##
As noted, images of these scorecards are everywhere and the team needs to get image files easily. My original thought was to use SVG Crowbar to pry these out of the browser, so I set about making them out of pure SVG. Unfortunately, the images never came out with their CSS styling attached. Installing a Chrome extension to pry out images from a website is a bit of a big ask for most users anyway, so I abandoned this path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searching for another way, I looked into using html canvas and libraries that convert these into image files. Perfect, I thought, not using HTML/CSS for text layout sucks anyway! I ripped everything up and started over with a much more semantic approach, and found happily that &lt;a href=&quot;http://cburgmer.github.io/rasterizeHTML.js/&quot;&gt;rasterizeHTML&lt;/a&gt; does a great job of converting the screen graphics, even going between retina and non-retina displays. My design also got lighter and better once I had some of my old friends like “border” and “div” back in town. Everybody wins!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example I downloaded from the browser as a .png:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/SA-scorecard.png&quot; alt=&quot;New scorecard&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Redesigned redesign of SPI scorecards.&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I began working on these, a number of coworkers have gotten interested in using R for their work, so I’ve eliminated the calculations in JavaScript and have instead been working to port the code for generating strength/weaknesses values to R. Now a very large datasheet feeds the web app a straight value for the color of each dot. To make it so anyone at this organization can generate a new set of scorecards, I’ve also created an InDesign template and used data merge to create the full set of cards. The resulting images are much sharper (rasterizeHTML does a good job, but it’s not a pro designer tool), and, in the end, I think this is a more flexible and smart arrangement, especially because the new site design doesn’t include a natural home for these webified scorecards anyway. :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/EU-scorecards.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Scorecard for EU Regional Social Progress Index&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Redesigned redesigned redesign of SPI scorecards.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2016 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/update/2016/05/10/scorecards.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/update/2016/05/10/scorecards.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Election Map For Partnership For A New American Economy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.renewoureconomy.org/voterinteractive/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/elexmap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.renewoureconomy.org/voterinteractive/&quot;&gt;first interactive&lt;/a&gt; I worked on as an actual professional being paid cash money. I was the main developer on the project, with a lot of guidance from my excellent colleague, Reed Spool, for which I will always be grateful. I got a lot better at d3 and JavaScript after this project!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2015 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/update/2015/12/26/new-american-econ.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/update/2015/12/26/new-american-econ.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Business Cards &amp; TED Slides</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A few projects from late 2015:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/bizcards.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Biz card&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I designed new business cards for the Social Progress Imperative. This organization has employees in many different countries, so we elected to leave off a location and make the website our home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000/assets/TED-slide.png&quot; alt=&quot;TED slides&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I created slides for our director’s second &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ted.com/talks/michael_green_how_we_can_make_the_world_a_better_place_by_2030?language=en&quot;&gt;TED Talk&lt;/a&gt; given in London last September at TED Global. The scatterplot is a perennial at SPI, since our mission is to advance this index as a measure of things left out of GDP, notably the things that actually make life better. The fact that some countries are so far over or under the curve demonstrates that GDP doesn’t automatically convert to what we describe as “social progress”, as measured by “indicators” like “water and sanitation”, “access to basic knowledge”, “nutrition and basic medical care”, “personal rights”, etc for a whole society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I focused on making these legible from far away in a dark room: dark background, strong contrast, minimal markings on the charts. Reportedly (via Michael Green) these received compliments from the TED Global people!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/update/2015/10/15/biz-cards-and-slides.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/update/2015/10/15/biz-cards-and-slides.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Birds Of Prey!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/projects/birdsofprey.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/birdsofprey.png&quot; alt=&quot;Birds of prey&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was looking around for some design prompts online and found a decent collection at &lt;a href=&quot;http://briefbox.me&quot;&gt;Briefbox&lt;/a&gt;. The first prompt to catch my eye asked for an infographic on &lt;a href=&quot;http://briefbox.me/design-brief/birds-of-prey-infographic/&quot;&gt;“birds of prey”&lt;/a&gt;. The Briefbox people suggest looking at Wikipedia, which I did, only to be overwhelmed and bored by an academic account of phylogenic studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The phylogeny of Accipitriformes is complex and difficult to unravel. Widespread paraphylies were observed in many phylogenetic studies. Unfortunately more recent and detailed studies are shown similar results. However, according to the findings of a 2014 study, the sister relationship between larger clades of Accipitriformes was well supported (e.g. relationship of Harpagus kites to buzzards and sea eagles and these latter two with Accipiter hawks are sister taxa of the clade containing Aquilinae and Harpiinae).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While science is totally of amazing, sometimes the way it’s presented on Wikipedia just makes one despair* of finding enough interesting, linear nuggets to make a little infographic story. So what did I do? I made some shit up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have also used &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.catipsum.com/&quot;&gt;Cat Ipsum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Meowing non stop for food plan steps for world domination but lick arm hair. Find something else more interesting intently stare at the same spot lick butt, for hate dog poop on grasses, chase laser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Yeah, but… not for long! I learned about the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Secretarybird&quot;&gt;secretarybird&lt;/a&gt; from this article. Have you seen this thing??&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2015 18:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/update/2015/06/11/birds-of-prey.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/update/2015/06/11/birds-of-prey.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mapping Jobs Data</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/projects/census/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/jobmap.png&quot; alt=&quot;Screenshot of map&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve done a few basic heatmaps at work and wanted to take what I had learned and put it toward some “interesting” data. I thought it would be fun to do something with the 2012 Economic Census, so I put together &lt;a href=&quot;/projects/census/index.html&quot;&gt;this piece&lt;/a&gt; that displays either the “job births” or “job destructions” counted in each of our nation’s 280+ lovely MSAs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of my time so far has been spent on organizing the program to work efficiently. Since there are 8 survey years available (1977 to 2012), 280+ MSAs and something like 5 subcategories for each (depending on business size/age) preserving this dataset inside the program as something you can work with takes quite a bit of folding and unfolding. I found Shan Carter’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://bl.ocks.org/shancarter/raw/4748131/&quot;&gt;Mister Nester&lt;/a&gt; to be an invaluable tool for wrapping my head around nesting functions in D3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I have at this point is a basic, functioning map. I’d like to one day take advantage of the data set better by setting up some filtering options. As mentioned, the data identifies companies by size and age. Since there’s always so much chatter about the importance of small businesses being “job creators” I thought it would be interesting to see if any trends become evident on the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making this map also made me think about how, in some ways, every heatmap/quantity map just becomes a map of the population. In this map, clearly New York and other large cities create and lose a ton of jobs. They also have a ton of people. I wonder whether adding a basic population heatmap as the base of the whole project would provide meaningful context.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Mar 2015 11:54:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/03/21/job-map.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/03/21/job-map.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
