<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JoElla Carman</title>
    <description>A place for charts and graphs.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 17:17:51 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 17:17:51 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Housing First</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;
July 15, 2021
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.urban.org/features/housing-first-breaks-homelessness-jail-cycle&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/denver-hed-lg.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This illustration features people whose lives were improved by an experimental housing program in Denver, CO, along with some of the items that help make their new apartments “home.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge here was expressing that idea with an already heavily-used set of commissioned photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To create a fresh take, I worked with contrasts—of size, color, lightness, and balance. Anchoring the composition is a faded image of a downtown Denver street scene. Against that, a proud, crisp face shows the clarity and happiness that comes with having a place to be. These contrasts speak to the transformative power of home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This image received many accolades from the broader team and serves as a dynamic introduction to a summary of the study’s findings.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 11:54:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2021/07/15/housing-first.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2021/07/15/housing-first.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The unequal commute</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;
October 6, 2020
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you show not just how far potential workers are from jobs, but how difficult (and likely) it is for them to get there?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This quick turn feature highlights a new way to measure equity in transportation planning that considers just that issue: access to jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our challenge as the comms team was to make this complex measure easy to understand. A choropleth map is great for spatial data and worked well here to highlight the problem areas leaders should target with more funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also needed to make it easy for a reader to find a particular neighborhood on the map. The data is calculated by Census block group, not very intuitive for most people. Mapbox, with its built-in layer of roads and landmarks, was a great solution. Making that base layer visible through the data overlay required a lot of careful thought and experimentation with color, opacity, and layering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end result is a beautiful, textured map that’s easy to navigate and clearly identifies neighborhoods in need of additional transit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.urban.org/features/unequal-commute&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/bmore-commute.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2019 11:54:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/10/06/unequal-commute.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/10/06/unequal-commute.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Trump at the G20</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;
June 26, 2019
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Melding three different photos with different lighting, exposures, etc., into a composite that looks natural can be a challenge. Even more so if you don’t want to ground the silhouettes at the bottom of the frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Designers at CNN Politics often used organic-verging-on-angular lines at the bottom of the figures to solve this problem, as I did for this quick turn piece on Kevin Liptak’s story &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/06/26/politics/donald-trump-xi-jinping-vladimir-putin-g20-meetings/index.html&quot;&gt;Trump’s G20 orbits around Xi, Putin, and other world leaders&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/06/26/politics/donald-trump-xi-jinping-vladimir-putin-g20-meetings/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/trump-putin-xi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2019 11:54:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/06/26/g20-photo-illustration.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/06/26/g20-photo-illustration.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who qualified to debate</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;
May 10, 2019
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018, the DNC had a complicated set of rules for selecting which candidates out of a wide field would actually take the stage at the debate. My challenge was to show who had made the cut quickly and easily, and to help readers keep track of the candidates, many of whom were not household names.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I focused the graphic on a broad expression of the main criteria for the debate: individual donors and polling. The blue box highlights values that meet the criteria, so readers can tell at a glance who has qualified. I also include the actual value of unique donors as a point of interest. The details of the rules are handled in the deck head and the rest of the article.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To help readers with the who’s who I used head shots, but not before doing some serious retouching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many months as the 2020 race ramped up at CNN we made do with a set of mismatched photos rather than true head shots. To include them all on such an angular, graphic and brilliantly blue chart I needed to bring some consistency. High-contrast black and white bought a lot of uniformity across the set and really helped make the people identifiable and gave the graphic some interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/05/09/politics/democratic-primary-debates-tracking-qualifications-polling-fundraising/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/debate-qualified.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new set of photos turned out to have pretty good legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Colbert Show used a &lt;a href=&quot;/assets/LateShow.jpg&quot;&gt;bar chart&lt;/a&gt; I made with the same set of heads on a July 2019 quarterly fund raising segment. The graphic above was included in an  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/videos/politics/2019/06/13/how-to-qualify-for-a-presidential-debate-mh-orig.cnn&quot;&gt;explainer&lt;/a&gt; on the debates for CNN’s social channels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 11:54:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/05/10/qualified-for-dem-debates.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/05/10/qualified-for-dem-debates.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tax cuts and refunds</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;
April 13, 2019
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This graphic ran with the story &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/04/13/politics/tax-reform-winners-and-losers/index.html&quot;&gt;Here’s who’s winning under Trump’s tax law&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started out by making bar chart so the individual states could be identified, but this buried the real takeaway: refunds shrank only in blue states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I let go of individual state labels in favor of showing the red/blue grouping and it became a more concise and effective piece.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/04/13/politics/tax-reform-winners-and-losers/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/tax-cuts.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the fact, I learned the name for &lt;a href=&quot;https://blockbuilder.org/mbostock/6526445e2b44303eebf21da3b6627320&quot;&gt;“beeswarm”&lt;/a&gt; charts. I wished I had learned it earlier because it would have been great here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 11:54:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/04/13/tax-breaks-and-refunds.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/04/13/tax-breaks-and-refunds.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>DHS after the purge</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;
April 17, 2019
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The team working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/04/17/politics/inside-dhs-after-the-purge/index.html&quot;&gt;this story&lt;/a&gt; was captivated by this photo of a ribbon-cutting ceremony showing a number of soon-to-be-replaced officials and acting or otherwise temporary leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Direct notation is a handy (and cool) way to make it easy for a reader to see your point. Here it works well to note officials that are coming and going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/04/17/politics/inside-dhs-after-the-purge/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/dhs-purge.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Illustration of Kirstjen Nielsen and Claire Grady with their replacements, Kevin McAleenan and David Pekoske.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 11:54:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/23/dhs-purge.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/03/23/dhs-purge.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Age range of candidates</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;
March 23, 2019
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This look at the generational spread of the Democratic field was inspired by Pete Buttigieg’s comment that his own youthful face was “the message” of his campaign. He told Morning Joe: “That’s why I often talk about how the world’s going to look in 2054, when I get to the current age of the current president. It’s to remind us that this isn’t just about one election.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what year will it be (or was it) when other candidates are 72, like Trump?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/03/23/politics/2020-presidential-race-generation-gap/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/pres-cand-age.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the charts I make at CNN use templates. It’s a sane way to handle daily graphics flow for many reasons, but one does enjoy a chance to get creative especially on a somewhat evergreen topic of candidate age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I spent a few days workshopping this chart with colleagues. The first feature to stay were the gray columns for generational bands. This is something I’ve seen Pew Research center do a number of times and makes a lot of sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also wanted to highlight the distance from age 72 for each candidate (and enjoyed the patter this creates).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On mobile, however, I took this out since it’s not original information (it’s not hard to get that 37 is indeed a long way from 72).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CNN has since updated this same graphic and used it again in another piece to capture search interest in candidates’ age.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2019 11:54:02 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/23/candidate-generations.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/03/23/candidate-generations.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Presidential vetoes</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;
March 3, 2019
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though it seems odd to think this would happen today, in the past many presidents have vetoed legislation from their own party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/03/02/politics/trump-presidents-veto-congress-history-override-national-emergency/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/vetoes.png&quot; alt=&quot;Scatterplot of presidential vetoes since 1789&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 10:54:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/03/03/presidential-vetoes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/03/03/presidential-vetoes.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2020 Dems shift left</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;
February 13, 2019
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harry Enten crunched some fascinating numbers on political ideology and I captured them in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/02/12/politics/2020-democratic-field-more-liberal-than-past-years/index.html&quot;&gt;a graphic&lt;/a&gt;. Possibly my best piece of work for CNN so far is the donkey icon on this graph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2019/02/12/politics/2020-democratic-field-more-liberal-than-past-years/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/enten-dem-cand-ideology.png&quot; alt=&quot;The average of 2020 frontrunners' ideological score according to VoteView.com is more liberal than past candidates'.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 10:54:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2019/02/13/average-dem-cands-shift-left.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2019/02/13/average-dem-cands-shift-left.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Women in Congress</title>
        <description>&lt;p class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;
November 9, 2018
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2018 set a record for the number of women in Congress. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2018/11/07/politics/history-making-night-for-women/index.html&quot;&gt;This story&lt;/a&gt; by Maeve Reston marks the occasion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2018/11/07/politics/history-making-night-for-women/index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/women-in-congress.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Dot chart of women in the House and Senate.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 10:54:02 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/11/09/women-in-congress.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/11/09/women-in-congress.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
